Jon Vincent

Englewood, CO 80110 jon.vincent@spyrafall.com +1 773 575 9655

Software developer and team leader with over fifteen years of experience and diverse domain expertise that includes building solutions supporting business operations and CAD. Able to lead global teams in project efforts, mentor junior developers, and interface with customers to gather requirements.

Work Experience

Sr. Full Stack Developer

Apex Systems - Denver, CO October 2018 to Present

- Created systems for internal corporate customers using Golang as the back end and React for the front end.
- Front Door intake system Streamlined the request intake process for C-level executives by working directly with the product owners to build a new application.
- Integrated with Jira and Clarity PPM APIs for seamless business interactions.
- Architect of a webhook system that centralized the source of truth for existing systems and allowed for a simple subscription process for new systems.
- Created a cron based system for adding profiles to Apple TV devices using the Apple Set-Top box API.

Lead Software Developer - Business Applications Team Lead

NCH Software - Denver, CO June 2011 to October 2018

- Oversaw four in-house developers and three remotes building PC-based business applications for invoicing, POS, CRM, personal finance, and time management. The apps are all written in C++ and ported by remote teams to Mac, iOS, and Android.
- Built Brisk Invoicing, a cloud-based invoicing application using JavaScript, CSS, and MySQL with a proprietary server built in C++.
- Integrated Express Invoice application with the Dropbox API to allow for persistent syncing between installations over users' multiple devices. The app supports PC, Mac, iOS, and Android platforms.
- Created MoneyLine, a personal finance management application that accesses financial institutions using the OFX standard. Built in six months using C++ and SQLite.
- Led daily scrums and mentored development teams during a period when sales of NCH's business software increased every month, outperforming all six divisions of the company.

Senior Development Professional

Instep Software LLC (now Schneider Electric) - Chicago, IL September 2001 to September 2009

· eDNA Billing System -Designed, maintained, and oversaw development in C#/.NET and Oracle to integrate billing departments and the facility management teams of universities and government

institutions. Met with user groups and led discussion sessions to gain understanding of users' work processes.

- \cdot PRiSM Developed a neural network API in C#/.NET used for diagnosing the cause of anomalies discovered by PRiSM's (power plant failure detection software) predictive analysis.
- · Client Management Tool Maintained and added features to customer service tool written in Java used by in person and service center representatives.
- · SI Explorer Constructed Smithsonian's property explorer for the facilities management department that displays interactive floor plans over the web and allows users to analyze exhibit information visually using AutoDesk's MapGuide software and JavaScript. Integrated GIS data with Google Maps API.
- · Engineering Document Management System Developed a low-latency enterprise application in VB that replicates documents and their attributes between remote offices for Office, AutoCAD, and MicroStation files.
- · iMove Created a collision detection and analysis tool in C++ using the Bentley library that models power plant equipment replacement. It's used in a 3D model to determine if large industrial equipment can be moved safely.
- · Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) Compiler -Built a server side tool using C++ and a web interface that converts AutoCad and MicroStation files into files which can be parsed by an SVG viewer. Created a web-based redlining tool using SVG.
- \cdot A/E/C Workspace and File Manager Developed enhancements and maintained code base for the US Army Corps of Engineers using the CAD Standards and Details libraries.

Developer

RB Digital - Chicago, IL March 2000 to July 2001

Designed easy-to-use tools and applications for website maintenance. Used PERL and SQL to create secure online commerce for business-to-business operations.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

DePaul University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Valparaiso University

Skills

- Kubernetes
- Unix
- Perl
- PostgreSQL
- Machine Learning
- SQLite
- MS SQL Server
- C++

- CI/CD
- Docker
- Javascript
- engineering applications (AutoCAD
- Windows
- Golang
- C#
- Oracle
- Bentley products)
- React
- Java
- multi-threaded algorithms
- SQL
- MySQL
- Jira
- Agile
- REST
- Node.js
- Computer Science
- GitHub
- Bootstrap
- CSS
- MongoDB
- AWS
- Application Development
- Software Development
- HTML5